Reuben Kadish
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Pollock, Charles and Sylvia: undated and 1972-1990 (18 letters)
Pollock, Jackson: 1944-1947 (5 letters)
Pollock-Krasner Foundation: 1988-1992 (6 letters)
Polyn, Winifred: 1989 (1 postcard)
Port Authority of N.Y. & N.J.: 1979 (1 letter)
Potter, Jeffrey: 1990-1991 (2 letters, including a typescript “A Note on Joseph Meert”)
Pound, Brandy: 1976 (1 letter); see Kadish, Reuben
Preston, Joanna: 1969-1989 (11 letters)
Printmaking Workshop: 1976-1980 (4 letters)
Pritchard, Norman: 1976 (1 Christmas card)
Provost, Larry: 1990 (1 letter)
Pye, Elizabeth: 1970 (1 letter)
Queens College: 1969 (2 letter)
Racz, David: undated (1 postcard)
Rantz, Clark T.: 1979 (1 letter)
Rapee, George and Jody: 1992 (1 letter)
Reddy, Krishna: 1974-1980 (1 letter and 9 letters from other concerning Reddy, including one letter from Stanley William Hayter)
Reed, Susan: see Kadish, Reuben
Reim, Johannes and Lois Borgenicht: 1987 (1 birth announcement)
Renfro, Claudia: undated and 1988-1992 (7 letters, including an illustrated Christmas card)
Resika, Paul: 1989 (1 postcard)
Richards: 1990 (2 photographs of a man with a child)
Richardson, Louise and Joe: undated and 1985-1986 (1 letter and 3 Christmas cards)
Ringwood Manor Association of Arts: 1975 (1 letter)
Ripton, June and James: 1984-1986 (3 Christmas cards)
Rodriguez, Melinda and Nickolas: 1989-1991 (4 letters, including a photograph of Nickolas); see Kadish, Reuben
Roecker and Gnazzo: 1986 (1 postcard)
Root, William Pitt: see Masini, Donna
Ross, Tim: 1985 (illustrated New Year's announcement)
Ru, Ridley: see San, Tamar
Ruben, Richards: 1991 (1 wedding announcement)
Rubenfeld, Florence: 1989 (2 letters)
Rubinson, Karen S.: 1987 (1 letter)
Sacartoff, Elizabeth: 1946 (3 letters)
San, Tamar, and Ridley Ru: undated (1 letter)
San Francisco Friends of the Urban Forest: 1993 (1 certificate for memorial trees for Reuben and Barbara Kadish)
Saunders, David: 1988 (1 letter)
Schor: Ilya Schor Foundation, Inc.: 1963 (1 letter)
Schramm, James S.: 1961 (1 letter)
Schwartz, Ersy: 1974-1983 (2 letters)
Schwartz, Jan and Hank: undated and 1976-1995 (3 letters)
Schwebel, Ivan: 1961-1991 (7 letters, including 6 illustrated letters)
Sears, Arthur Wellington (Pete): 1937 (1 letter)
Selby, Sally and James: 1969-1988 (8 letters and 1 postcard)
Shaltiel, J.: undated (1 postcard)
Shirer, Tess: 1984 (1 Christmas card)
Silverman, Joan and Charlie: 1971 (3 letters and 1 postcard)
Silverman, Pauline: 1972 (2 letters)
Silverstein, Sasha: 1989 (1 exhibition announcement)
Sirugo, Sol: 1977 (1 letter)
Smith, Benjamin B.: 1976 (2 letters)
Sokoloff, Beryl: 1944-1992 (21 letters)
South Bank Show: 1987 (2 letters)
Spanish Bay Galleries: 1991 (1 illustrated letter)
Spring, Bob: see Kadish, Reuben
Stable Gallery: 1958 (1 letter)
Stanzl, Gouter: 1970 (1 letter)
Stark, Leonard: undated and 1937-1966 (73 letters, including one with illustrations, one enclosing a cut-out silhouette portrait, one enclosing a photograph of a boy with a raccoon and one, dated 1947, enclosing a photograph of a film shoot with Georgia O'Keeffe)
Stewart, Jack: 1972 (1 postcard)
Stony Brook: 1990-1992 (6 letters)
Sun, Carol: 1990 (2 letters, including an exhibition announcement and clippings)
Suzuki, Margi: 1962 (1 letter)
Szeto, Nam: 1991 (1 letter, including a resume)
Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc.: 1961-1969 (4 letters)
Taylor, John Lloyd: 1975 (3 letters)
Tebow, Elizabeth: 1982-1992 (3 illustrated Christmas cards)
Teller, Jane: 1986 (1 letter)
Terry, James G.: 1948 (1 letter)
The Gallery: 1969 (1 exhibition prospectus)
Toombs, Amisano & Wells: 1970 (1 letter)
Tully, Judd: undated and 1985-1992 (10 letters)
Umbreit, William and Cindy: 1968-1980 (2 letters)
University of Oregon: see Oregon: University of Oregon
Unver, Huseyin: 1968 (2 letters)
Vergette, Helen: 1978 (1 postcard)
Vidal, Francine: 1986 (1 letter)
Vulliemoz, Yvonne: 1987-1995 (1 postcard and 1 Christmas card)
Waxman, Wendy: 1989 (1 letter)
Wayne, June: see Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc.
Weatherspoon Art Gallery: 1973 (1 letter)
Weeks, Leigh K.: 1974-1987 (2 letters)
Welles, Halsted (Hal): undated and 1962-1966 (3 postcards and a calling card)
Wibroe-Sanders, Suzi: 1989-1990 (2 letters)
Williams, Govaine: 1986 (1 letter)
Williams, Julian and Le: undated and 1977-1990 (1 letter, 1 wedding invitation, and 3 Christmas cards [2 with photos of microbes and a forest])
Wines, Gul and Suzan: 1986 (1 Christmas card)
Witkin, Joy: 1990 (1 letter)
Wong, Jimmy, and Songsri Chang: 1985 (1 Christmas card)
Wood, Betty: 1975 (1 letter and a postcard)
Woodward/White, Inc.: 1983 (1 letter)
Works Progress Administration - California: 1937 (1 letter)
Wu, Nancy: 1987 (6 letters)
Zogbaum, Wilfrid: 1960-1962 (2 letters)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
De Kooning, Willem, 1904-; Guston, Philip, 1913-; Langsner, Jules, 1911-1967; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956; Siqueiros, David Alfaro
Subjects-Topical:
Muralists -- California; Sculptors -- California; Sculptors -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews
Types of Materials:
Drawings; Photographs
Names:
Ashton, Dore; Cherry, Herman; Conant, Howard Somers, 1921-; Hiler, Hilaire, 1898-1966; Neininger, Urban; Pollock, Charles C.; Tully, Judd
Provenance
The eight photographs on Reel 5660 were donated to the Archives of American Art in 1984 by Reuben Kadish. The other material on Reels 5655-5660 was lent for filming in 1998 by Morris and Ruth Kadish, brother and sister-in-law of Reuben Kadish, and executors of his estate, and subsequently donated to the Archives of American Art in 2002.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use of microfilmed material requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington D.C. facility. Microfilmed portion must be consulted on microfilm.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection is available on microfilm reels 5655-5660. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1938-1992, Series 1:; (box 1, 2 folders)
  This series includes nineteen résumés, and various identification documents such as a copy of Kadish's birth certificate, a driver's license, a social security card, a war correspondent special pass, and a passport.
  - Résumés, 1978-1990, (2 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Personal papers, 1938-1992 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
- Letters, 1934-1995, undated, Series 2:; (boxes 1-3, 2.5 linear ft.)
  Letters found here are from friends and colleagues including Herman Cherry, Philip Guston, Hilaire Hiler, Jules Langsner, Urban Neininger, Charles Pollock, and Jackson Pollock. One letter from the Leonard Stark family contains a small photograph of Georgia O'Keeffe. Some of the folders contain letters from a single correspondent, and some contain a range of correspondents, all of whom are not listed in the folder title. A complete list of correspondents, including details about the number and types of items from each correspondent, supplements the container list below and can be found in the Appendix.
  The letters are arranged alphabetically by name of sender.
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1936-1990, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Correspondents identified by first name only, 1962-1995, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Advanced Design, 1989 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Agee, Jon and Carol, 1982-1991, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Albert, Calvin - Archaeometry (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Archives of American Art, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Archives of the New York School - Artists for CORE (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Artists for SEDF (Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Inc.), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Arts Commission of San Francisco, 1988 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Aruz, Joanna, 1972-1986 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Ashford, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Ashton, Dore and Matti, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Atasoy, Sumer, 1970-1972, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Auerbach - Axe, Martin (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - B., F. - Barnes Foundation (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Barnett: David Barnett Gallery, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Barnoya, Miguel Benedict - Beeblitz, Patricia (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Benson, Elaine M. (Benson Gallery) - Biddle, George (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Bigman, Stephanie - Bohen, Barbara (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Borgenicht: Grace Borgenicht Gallery, Inc., 1977-1993 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Bourne, Robert B., 1989-1992 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Braczyk, Robert - Braunstein, V. (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Briggs, Eta and A., 1962-1969, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Buto, Gian (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Cadwalader, Stephen, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Canizaro, James T. - CDS Gallery (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Cherry, Herman (see also Series 3: Writings), 1958-1992, (5 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Chui, Kam Wah - Click, Ashley (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Cohn, Susanne, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Committee of Artists for Greek Relief - Contreras, Belisario (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Cooper Union, 1962-1991 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Copley, Al L. - Crawford (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Davis, Bruce - Dehner, Dorothy (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Democratic National Committee - Duback, Charles (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Dugmore, Edward and Eadie, 1959-1992, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Einstein: G. W. Einstein Co., Inc., 1991-1992 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Elston Fine Arts - Engelman, Martin (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Erim, Kenan, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Fanshel, Florence - Frumkin: Allan Frumkin Gallery, Inc. (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Galerie de Seine - Gerard, C. H. Coster (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - German, Mrs. Ulker, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Gerstenblith, Patty, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Goerits, Mathias - Graham Gallery, Ltd. (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Graham, Lanier (Australian National Gallery), 1984-1990 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Greenfield-Sanders, Timothy - Greyhound Travel Services, Inc. (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Guggenheim Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Guston, Philip, 1936-1976, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Hackman, William - Harris, George (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Hauptmann, H. (Freie Universitat Berlin) - Hesse, Brian (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Hiler, Hilaire, 1941-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Hios, Theo - Hurlburt, Larry (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Independent Curators, Inc., 1988-[1990] (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Irwin, Lani, and Alan Feltus, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Istituto Nazionale per la Grafica, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Jackman - Johnson, Daniel LaRue (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Johnson: Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, 1987 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Johnson, Una E. - Jorgensen, Henry and Elizabeth (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Barbara, 1963-1974, undated (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Dan, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, David, 1990 (Box 1, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Frank and Lorain, 1983-1991 (Box 2, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Jonathan - Kadish, Julian (Box 2, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Kennan, 1970-1990 (Box 2, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Morris [Moishe] and Ruth (see also Kadish, Reuben), 1973-1998, (3 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Philip, 1990, undated (Box 2, Reel 5655)
  - Kadish, Reuben, 1967-1992, undated, (9 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5655-5656)
  - Kaufman, B. John - Kettenbach, Friedel (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Klayman, Toby Judith - Kroeplin, Jim (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Kupferman, Lawrence, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - L., Howard - Landmark Gallery, Inc. (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Langsner, Jules, 1937-1963, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Lebt?, Bill, 1967 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Lee, Jenny (see also Kadish, Reuben), 1985-1992, undated, (7 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Leggist?, Gihuan - Lesher, Derek (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Levine, Marsha, 1973-1986, undated, (12 letters) (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Life magazine - Lukela?, Bob (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Lynch, Bill, 1991, undated (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Magnes: Judah L. Magnes Museum - Mallary, R. (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Mandel, Johanna and Aaron, 1974-1991 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Manhattanville College - Manning (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Marciano, Shirley, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Marcus, Joel - Martin, Fletcher (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Masini, Donna, and William Pitt Root, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Mason, William and Melanie - Matlin, David and Gail (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Mayer, Musa (Ingie) (see also Kadish, Reuben), 1987-1989 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - McCoy, Sande (nee Pollock), 1935-1986, undated (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - McDermott, Paul M. - McHale, Rachel (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - McLaughlin, Janie, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Menil Collection - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Mexican Muralists in the United States: Their Work and Influence (NEH research project), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Michigan State University - Mirski, Boris (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Montgomery family, 1973-1986 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Moore, Lucile and Jim Al - Mythic Arts Africa (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - National Academy of Design - National Geographic Society (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - National Social Welfare Assembly, Inc. - NBC News (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Neininger, Urban and Jean, 1937-1989, undated, (28 letters) (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Nemanic, Todd - Newark Public School of Fine and Industrial Art (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Newbill, Al, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - New Jersey State Council on the Arts, 1989 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - New Jersey State Museum, 1976-1991 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - New York Civil Liberties Union, 1972 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - New York Studio School, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - New York University - North Jersey Cultural Council (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - O'Connell, Hilda (see also Kadish, Barbara), 1963-1990, undated (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Odate, Gerlinde - Oord, A. and B. (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Oregon: University of Oregon, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Reel 5656)
  - Pace, Stephen, 1976-1987 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Panero, Lorenza (Laurie, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Parsons School of Design, 1991 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Pekarsky, Mel, 1992 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Perrone, Francis S., M.D. - Phillips, Bill and Helen (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Pollock, Charles and Sylvia, 1972-1990, undated (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Pollock, Jackson, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Pollock-Krasner Foundation, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Polyn, Winifred - Pound, Brandy (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Preston, Joanna, 1969-1989 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Printmaking Workshop, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Pritchard, Norman - Pye, Elizabeth (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Queens College, 1969 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Racz, David - Rapee, George and Jody, 1992 (Box 3, Reel 5656)
  - Reddy, Krishna, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Reel 5656-5657)
  - Reim, Johannes and Lois Borgenicht, 1987 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Renfro, Claudia, 1988-1992, undated (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Resika, Paul - Ringwood Manor Association of Arts (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Ripton, June and James, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Rodriguez, Melinda and Nickolas (see also Kadish, Reuben), 1989-1991 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Roecker and Gnazzo - Rubinson, Karen S. (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Sacartoff, Elizabeth - Schwartz, Jan and Hank (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Schwebel, Ivan, 1961-1991 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Sears, Arthur Wellington (Pete) - Selby, Sally and James (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Shaltiel, J. - Smith, Benjamin B. (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Sokoloff, Beryl, 1944-1992 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - South Bank Show - Stanzl, Gouter (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Stark, Leonard, 1937-1966, undated, (11 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Stewart, Jack - Szeto, Nam (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc. - Toombs, Amisano & Wells (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Tully, Judd, 1985-1992, undated (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Umbreit, William and Cindy - Unver, Huseyin (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Vergette, Helen - Vulliemoz, Yvonne (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Waxman, Wendy - Wibroe-Sanders, Suzi (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Williams, Govaine - Works Progress Administration, California (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Wu, Nancy, 1987 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Zogbaum, Wilfrid, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
- Personal Business Records, 1952-1995, Series 3:; (boxes 3-4, 37 folders)
  Personal business records consist of legal documents and financial records. The legal documents include estate papers for both Ida and Reuben Kadish, leases and rent agreements, miscellaneous documents concerning the New Jersey farm, and miscellaneous contracts. Financial records include income tax records, banking records, applications for grants, consignment and sales records, and receipts for medical care, utilities, art supplies and art-related services.
  - Legal documents, 1953-1994, 3.1:
    Leases and rental agreements include an undated floorplan of the 229 East 9th Street building. Miscellaneous contracts include a 1989 contract with the Graham Gallery in New York and a 1961 timber sale contract.
    - Ida Kadish estate papers, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Reuben Kadish estate papers, 1961-1994 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Leases and rent agreements, 1953-1976, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Miscellaneous documents concerning the N.J. farm, 1975-1990 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Miscellaneous contracts, 1961, 1989, (7 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Affidavit concerning sculpture by Jackson Pollock, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
    - Life insurance policies, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Reel 5657)
  - Financial records, 1952-1995, 3.2:
    - Income tax records, 1962-1992, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Banking records, 1961-1995, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Medical receipts, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Receipts concerning automobiles, 1952-1987 (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Receipts for utilities, 1962-1992 (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Receipts for hardware and art supplies, and framing services, 1965-1995 (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Receipts for the casting of artwork, 1957-1991, (6 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Applications for grants and awards, 1970-1986, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5657)
    - Consignment and sales records, 1961-1993, (6 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
- Exhibition File, 1989-1991, Series 4:; (box 4, 1 folder)
  This exhibition file contains letters, loan agreement forms, an exhibition announcement, and a clipping relating to the 1990 exhibition Reuben Kadish: Works from 1930 to the Present.
  - Reuben Kadish: Works from 1930 to the Present, New Jersey State Museum, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Reel 5658)
- Notes, 1851-1853, 1937-1992, undated, Series 5:; (boxes 4-5, 35 folders)
  Notes consist of four address books, two gallery visitor registers, engagement calendars, and six notebooks containing miscellaneous names, telephone numbers, reminder notes, and medical information. There are also unbound notes on mural painting, printmaking, sculpture, and other art-related topics, and handwritten translations by William H. Thomson of thirty classic texts by Homer (Homer's Odyssey, Horace (Satires of Horace), and Demosthenes (Orations of Demosthenes), 1851-1853. Only the illustrated covers of the texts have been microfilmed.
  - Address books, 1985-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
  - Miscellaneous notes concerning addresses, 1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
  - Visitors' registers, 1985-1986, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
  - Engagement calendars, 1963, 1967, 1988-1989, 1991-1992, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
  - Notebooks, 1985-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5658)
  - Notebooks, 1989-1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5658)
  - Notes on artwork, art history, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, printmaking, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, mural painting, 1937-1938, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, ceramics and glazes, 1945-1957 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, sculpture, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, miscellaneous (including supply list for War Artist Unit, 1943), 1943-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes on artwork, concerning Cooper Union, 1974-1985 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Notes concerning medical matters (including 3 electrocardiograms), 1964-1983 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Handwritten translations by William H. Thomson, 1851-1853, (8 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
- Writings, 1975-1992, Series 6:; (box 5, 14 folders)
  Writings consist of an autobiographical manuscript by Kadish, and typescripts concerning Kadish and other art-related topics by other authors including Dore Ashton, Herman Cherry, Howard Conant, and Judd Tully.
  - Writings by Kadish, 1975-1992, 6.1:
    - Autobiographical manuscript, [1992], (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Writings by Others, 1963-1992, undated, 6.2:
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by author's name.
    - Typescript “Reuben Kadish, Man of Substance” by Dore Ashton, 1992 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “Reuben Kadish” by Jean Libman Block, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “Katsushika Hokusai: Thirty-Six Views of Mount Fuji” by Natalie Chereskin, 1977 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “Six Artists” by Herman Cherry, 1983 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Poems by R. Cherry, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Transcript of a speech “The Pursuit of Excellence” by Howard Conant, 1963 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “New Light on Pollock's Prints of 1943” by Lanier Graham, 1988 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript [“Albert Vanderburg”] by Edward Meneeley, [1966] (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “Action in Writing” by Shiryu Kiyoshi Morita, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “A Description of the Murals in Anderson Hall and the Science Building [at San Francisco State College]” by Fern Sargent, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript [Reuben Kadish] by Judd Tully, 1985 (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Miscellaneous poems by unidentified authors, 1975, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
    - Typescript “Self-Expressivity on Social Responsibility - A Contemporary American Artist, Reuben Kadish” by unidentified author, undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
- Artwork, 1981-1992, undated, Series 7:; (box 5, sol 10, 8 folders)
  Artwork consists of a hundred sketches and seventeen watercolors by Kadish, and artwork by others including an undated drawing for DIG (Archeology) by Barbara Kadish, and undated woven fabric designs mounted on cardboard.
  - Artwork by Kadish, sketches, 1981, undated, (4 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Artwork by Kadish, watercolors, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Artwork by others (see also sol 10), undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Artwork by others, woven fabric designs mounted on cardboard (2), undated (Box 5, Reel 5659)
- Printed Material, 1934-1993, undated, Series 8:; (boxes 5-7, 67 folders)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Kadish and others, reproductions of artwork, press releases, programs, miscellaneous catalogs for art schools and supplies, travel brochures, and picture postcards. Programs include a baseball program autographed by Darryl Strawberry, and programs for the Temple University Aegean Symposium 3, Christopher Mallory Wilmarth's funeral service, and Elaine De Kooning's memorial service.
  - Clippings, 1934-1946, 1960-1993, undated, (23 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5659)
  - Clippings (duplicates), 1934-1946, 1960-1993, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5659)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Kadish, 1937-1993, undated, (21 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5659)